## Gonçalo Cardoso Curriculum Vitae

Javascript Developer & Evangelist

## **Personal Info**

Full Name Gonçalo Cardoso Borges Ferreira

Date of Birth 7th August 1989

**Nationality** Portuguese

Phone 00351 91 857 17 46

Email & Website goncalo.cb.ferreira@gmail.com / www.gcardoso.pt

## **Summary**

About me

I'm an enthusiastic Javascript developer with a big passion for web and software development. Very professional with a great work ethic and a loyal worker that focuses on the best results. I have a powerful team spirit, a creative mind and a great sense of humour. Technically, I code not only with native object oriented Javascript but I also have experience working with many frameworks and libraries, such as AngularJS, React and jQuery. My front-end development approach follows the SEO rules and techniques as well as usability guidelines with performance awareness. The mobile compatibility is one of my main concerns so I'm always focused on making my applications work nice and smoothly on mobile devices. Given my passion about javascript, I'm also a co-organizer of a very well known and recognised javascript meetup in Lisbon, called require('lx').

## **Work Experience**

Date March 2015 to present

**Company** e.near - Nearshore Technology Solutions Software House @ Lisbon, Portugal

**Position held** Lead Javascript Developer

Main responsibilities I'm responsible for the development of mobile casino games, using mainly Javascript

for the frontend (2D Canvas & WebGL), backend (Node.js) and unit testing. As a team leader of a 10 people team, my main goal is to motivate and push them to deliver high quality games, taking the responsability of all the technical decisions made in the process. As a javascript specialist within the company, I'm also responsible for mentoring and teach all the other developers who work for other projects, to make sure they follow high quality code standards. I encoure the entire company to be aware about the cutting edge technologies by attending to conferences and meetups.

Date October 2013 to March 2015

**Company** StepValue - Web Intelligence Digital Marketing Agency @ Lisbon, Portugal

Position held Front-end Developer

Main responsibilities I was responsible for the front-end development of desktop and mobile web

applications, always focused on user experience, design, performance and responsive techniques, using the latest frameworks by that time, such as Angular JS and Kendo UI. Most of the web applications were single-page apps and the front-end was consumed by REST Api's, which required an asynchronous development approach.

Date October 2010 to October 2013

Company Portugal Telecom Information and Communication Technologies @ Lisbon, Portugal

**Position held** Front-end Developer

Main responsibilities I was responsible for the front-end development of desktop and mobile websites,

always focused on user experience, design, performance and responsive techniques using HTML5, CSS3 and Javascript. In addition, I was also concerned about cross-

browser compatibility, including the old ones like Internet Explorer 7.

I've worked with major portuguese clients such as Sport Lisboa e Benfica, Portugal Telecom, Portuguese Football Federation and Portuguese Navy. In the last two

projects besides developing my role was to lead the front-end team.

**Date** February 2008 to August 2008

**Company** Finepaper Graphic Design and Production @ Lisbon, Portugal

**Position held** Web developer - Part-time

Main responsibilities While I was studying, I tried to find an opportunity that could help me putting in

practice what I was learning in college, and Finepaper gave me that chance. I was responsible for the development of flash websites using the programming language

ActionScript 3.0, including the company's website.

**Education** 

Date October 2007 to July 2010

Course Multimedia Engineering

Degree Bachelor (Bologna Process)

**Institution** Instituto Superior de Tecnologias Avançadas

Final Grade 15 / 20

Main Subjects Software Engineering, Programming Languages, Web Development, Database

Management, Maths and Statistics, Video and Animation

**Main Skills** 

**Development** HTML5, CSS3, Javascript ES6 (Functional, Modular and Object Oriented), Node.js,

Single Page Applications, Progressive Enhancement, Graceful Degradation, Cross-

browser Compatibility, 2D Canvas, WebGL, Flux & Redux, Git & SVN

APIs REST APIs, Facebook Graph API, Google Maps API, Twitter API

**Javascript frameworks** React, AngularJS, Kendo UI, jQuery (UI and Mobile)

**Testing frameworks** Mocha, Cha, Selenium

Soft skills Enthusiastic, creativity, problem solving, teamwork, decision making, quick learning,

time management, team leadership, determination, responsibility, patience,

proactivity, accuracy, result-driven

**Interests** Swimming, walking, running, music, digital world, advertising, marketing, politics,

design, web development, programming, computer science, tech conferences and

meetups